Thank you for this beautiful introduction, Council General. It is an honor for
me that
you took the time to be here today from New York. Thank you so much, you made
my day very
special. I would like to congratulate past and present inductees and I am
privileged to be in
your company. And to those who recommended me for the International Hall of
Fame and voted for me,
thank you. You support and encouragement throughout the years is what inspired
me to produce the
weekly portfolio program, those past three years. And I am very grateful to my
listeners, sponsors,
friends, family, for your loyalty and support. I had a dream. I saw that
telling me in the world
that you are 55 years on the radio, maybe it was difficult, maybe it was hard,
but you know what,
the next 55 years will be very easy. In 1961, as the Council of General said,
my husband
and I started the portfolio program while raising our family and we were active
in many parts of
organization and how organized many cultural events. For many years in
operation, with the
state university, ethnic heritage studies, we were able to organize many great
ethnic cultural events.
It takes great pride. I think great pride and the part that my Polish program,
especially the
one on the ideas and the public radio is promoting Polish classical music
poetry and
poetry events where you can listen to Przykzowtent, Stanislaw Manuszko, Ignacy
Paderecki, Henry Genapski,
Wojcie Kieler, Karol Szczynowski, this is the music of the world's highest
quality.
In a radio interview with, I can many interviews with the evening program on
ideas stream and
one time when I interviewed Josh Raymond Kienkal, he said, "The new program is
a group that keeps
Colombia together." Thank you so much Josh. Some people would say that my major
show is unique and
many of my listeners tell me that they grew up listening to the Polish program
and that's one way
to keep with the Polish heritage. One place was during the banquet, he was
asked to speak and he said,
"I know as much Polish as I learned doing listening to the Eugenia sculpture
programs. I thought that
I will come from the chair, it was big audience like that. I love Polish music
and culture and I
am proud to have the privilege to promote it and enrich the lives of my
listeners. Thank you again
for this honor. Thank you so much for your presence.
[applause]